<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paessler Blog (EN)</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 10:11:31 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New handling of beta sensors in PRTG Network Monitor</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/new-handling-of-beta-sensors-in-prtg-network-monitor</link><description>In the blog article about PRTG release 21.1.65, I promised to tell you more about the experimental features in PRTG. The introduction of experimental features is accompanied by a new handling of beta sensors. Let’s have a look at exactly what this means, and what has changed.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 10:11:31 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/new-handling-of-beta-sensors-in-prtg-network-monitor</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Useful command line parameters for PRTG setup</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/useful-command-line-parameters-for-prtg-setup</link><description>Our goal at Paessler is to provide you with a straightforward installation process. All you need is to download and run the latest PRTG installer (309 MB) from our website, add your email address and license information and enjoy your coffee while PRTG gets to work. PRTG will run an initial auto-discovery as soon as the installation of PRTG is finished. It will automatically add devices that are able to respond to ICMP in your network as well as suitable sensors for monitoring.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:56:07 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/useful-command-line-parameters-for-prtg-setup</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>PRTG 21.1.65 contains beta sensors for HPE, Azure, Veeam and OPC UA</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-21.1.65-contains-beta-sensors-for-hpe-azure-veeam-and-opc-ua</link><description>The first stable release of 2021 for PRTG Network Monitor is here! By the way: PRTG release 21.1.65 is the 8th version in a row that our developers have programmed completely while working from home.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 11:45:12 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-21.1.65-contains-beta-sensors-for-hpe-azure-veeam-and-opc-ua</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Modular or all-in-one? Two different approaches in IT monitoring</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/modular-or-all-in-one-two-different-approaches-in-it-monitoring</link><description>The larger networks become, the more important it is to have an overview. IT decision-makers and IT administrators are faced with the question: "What is the right solution for my infrastructure?"
This question cannot be answered in one sentence, because many factors play an important role. First, it should be considered which information a monitoring solution must provide and how high the level of detail should be.</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 09:55:16 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/modular-or-all-in-one-two-different-approaches-in-it-monitoring</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>6 Challenges for Industrial IT over the next five years</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/6-challenges-for-industrial-it-over-the-next-five-years</link><description>Industrial IT has seen many changes over the past decade, with IT/OT convergence, Industry 4.0, and increased digitization all shaping the way the production floor connects and interacts with IT. And while we’ve already seen a lot of transformation in the industrial sphere, it’s also clear that it’s not stopping any time soon: By 2025, the IIoT market will be worth $110.6 billion, and this will only further drive the digitization trends we’ve seen so far.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 12:57:08 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/6-challenges-for-industrial-it-over-the-next-five-years</guid><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>Rhebo Industrial Protector – keeping the lights on</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/rhebo-industrial-protector-and-prtg</link><description>Industroyer, NotPetya, EKANS, Triton, LockerGoga. If those five words just sent a chill down your spine, chances are you work in the industrial control sector. For decades the OT world relied on “security through obscurity” to guarantee its safety – it’s difficult to attack a network that you can’t connect to. Unfortunately, for most companies, completely isolating their ICS environments from the outside world is no longer an option. Increased need for IT/OT convergence, remote access support demands from equipment vendors, and the need to collect, analyze&amp;nbsp;and store sensor data from IIoT applications all mean that industrial networks are increasingly connected to the outside world. Therefore, they are vulnerable to attack.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:22:27 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/rhebo-industrial-protector-and-prtg</guid><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>Would you like to expand your PRTG Linux monitoring?</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/would-you-like-to-monitor-linux-with-prtg</link><description>Ok, now that we have your attention… We are not kidding!
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 08:28:51 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/would-you-like-to-monitor-linux-with-prtg</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Measurement of CO₂ and other values in schools – why we should approach this task during and after the pandemic</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/measurements-of-co2-and-other-values-in-schools</link><description>If you are anything like me, you probably remember the smell of your old school building. As I write these lines, I have the distinct scent of my school's gym mats in my nose, as clearly as if I’m right now facing the terrible task of performing some stupid gymnastic exercise. The same goes for my former classroom: it was somehow musty, stale, steamy. And there was a reason for that: the air was fabulously bad. We know today that an excessively high proportion of CO₂ in the air can have disastrous consequences for concentration and that the levels become critical much earlier than instinctively suspected – depending on how many people are in a room, how old they are, how large their lung capacity is, and other factors. An already degraded air quality starts at 1,000 to about 1,400 ppm CO₂ in indoor air – we know that this value is often exceeded many times over in classrooms, even values of 2,000 up to 5,000 ppm can occur. This poses a risk, in the winter of the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic as well as during normal school operation.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 10:37:10 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/measurements-of-co2-and-other-values-in-schools</guid><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>Storage performance monitoring with PRTG</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/storage-performance-monitoring-with-prtg</link><description>Storage performance monitoring should be a standard part of every intelligent monitoring solution as it can have a major, positive impact on daily business. Find out why PRTG Network Monitor is the ideal solution for storage performance monitoring below.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 12:20:06 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/storage-performance-monitoring-with-prtg</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Get Certified with Paessler: Become a PRTG Monitoring Expert!</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/get-certified-with-paessler-become-a-prtg-monitoring-expert</link><description>Have you heard about Paessler Certified Monitoring Expert? It is a technical certification that goes hand in hand with our technical PRTG training. Our focus through our training and certification program is to empower and give our partners and customers enough knowledge to properly plan, demonstrate, install and to provide first-level support. Also, as a Monitoring Expert you can help your customers to choose the best license for certain architecture and sensor strategy design.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:00:11 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/get-certified-with-paessler-become-a-prtg-monitoring-expert</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Track the health status of physical servers via iDRAC, iLO, iRMC and IMM</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/get-alerted-on-physical-server-health-state-via-idrac-ilo-irmc-and-ipmi</link><description>We at Paessler are running heterogeneous network infrastructure powered by different physical servers such as Dell PowerEdge, HPE ProLiant, Fujitsu Primergy and IBM xSystem. Some of them are running as standalone servers and some are part of the cluster. One of the things I very much appreciate about managing my servers is the possibility to do it remotely, without even going to the server room and getting frozen, especially during the winter season. The remote management (hardware configuration, firmware upgrade or OS upgrade) can easily be done via management platforms/controllers/ports: iDRAC, iLO, iRMC and IMM – depending on the vendor.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 13:02:55 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/get-alerted-on-physical-server-health-state-via-idrac-ilo-irmc-and-ipmi</guid><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item><item><title>This was 2020 with PRTG. A review.</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-network-monitor-in-2020-a-review</link><description>Wow. 2020 was quite a hell ride for all of us! And I don't just mean us at Paessler, but really all of us. The whole planet experienced a rather exceptional year!
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 07:02:28 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-network-monitor-in-2020-a-review</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>You wouldn't believe what we've learned in one year after installing a PV system on our roof</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/what-weve-learned-in-one-year-after-installing-a-pv-system-on-our-roof</link><description>So, what happened to the photovoltaic system on our company roof? In short: It is still there. In a little longer: We couldn't be happier that we as a company are reducing our footprint on this earth by generating a significant portion of the electricity we use. We have been tracking our photovoltaic system, its output and our specific consumption for over a year now, and would like to give you a brief overview of our many insights.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 09:18:01 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/what-weve-learned-in-one-year-after-installing-a-pv-system-on-our-roof</guid><category>At the Paessler Office</category></item><item><title>We released version 20.3.0 of our PRTG iOS and Android App</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/we-released-version-20.3.0-of-our-prtg-ios-and-android-app</link><description>I regularly tell you here about the changes in the PRTG versions and the new sensors and features the software provides.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 15:25:53 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/we-released-version-20.3.0-of-our-prtg-ios-and-android-app</guid><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>INSYS icom + Node-RED + PRTG = Monitoring OT data</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/insys-icom-node-red-prtg-monitoring-ot-data</link><description>Frequent visitors, (that’s all of you, right?) may have noticed we’ve recently become very interested in technologies outside of traditional IT-focused monitoring. That’s not to say that we don’t still feel the love for all things “LAN, WAN, server &amp;amp; SAN”. But as most of us at Paessler are hardcore, self-confessed, uber-geeks, we just can’t resist the lure of shiny new tech to play with. That’s why many of our recent blog posts have an IoT or Industrial IoT focus. It’s not just blog posts either: our last few PRTG releases have included new sensor types, specifically for this exciting field – MQTT, Modbus and OPC-UA sensors are now all available in PRTG, and we’ve written extensively about enabling technologies that can help with the sometimes difficult task of merging the IT and OT worlds.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 16:00:48 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/insys-icom-node-red-prtg-monitoring-ot-data</guid><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item></channel></rss>
